# Olena Pustynska

## Interior Designer / Decorator

Portfolio: https://design-de-la-vie.github.io/

Email: <a href="mailto:darisher40@gmail.com">darisher40@gmail.com</a>
Phone: 07467691275

Highly-qualified designer, with an extraordinary experience. A passionate, and creative professional with 28 years of international experience, working on high-end residential and commercial interiors and environments. My goal is to obtain a job as an Interior Designer or Decorator in the UK.

### Skills

- Successfully working within the constraints of a limited budget, a small surface, and the need to accommodate all the necessary multi-functional units within a limited space, to guarantee a decent result for a small amount of money.
- Using design skills and tools to correct and transform flaws of an interior, thereby improving the overall impression of the interior.
- Able to solve difficult accomplishment tasks set by the client in a given room.
- Creating non-standard planning solutions
- Decorating display-windows, new products and collections placement, which allows the creation of a certain image and mood in the exposition, and as a consequence, attracts new customers.
- Develop schemes of individual furniture for the specific interior.
- Developing style and image concepts for various events, with the creation of decorative elements especially for the event.
- Creating decorations using different techniques, including the author's techniques.

- Preparing and composing a pre-sale design of houses, which allows to radically change
  the overall space of the interior, to present the building to potential buyers in the best
  way, with minimal cost and investment.
- Successful application and knowledge of the techniques of decorative stained-glass, tapestry, macramé, <u>paper-plastic</u>, and batik, as well as 2 self-developed techniques, the use of which allows giving a unique look to an interior.
- Creation of unique decorative elements for gift wrapping and presents for an individual client's event.
- Creation of customised interior elements, based on the general stylistics of the room, the colour solution and the technical requirements of the customer.
- Using the rules of ergonomics in the interior as a priority in the work on the project, and allows the creation of a safe and comfortable environment for the client.
- Applying psychological analysis when working with a client and on a project, in order to reflect the personality of the client in the interior, and match their personal requirements and comfort.
- Strict adherence to the functional relations and building regulations: working in-depth on the functional relations of spaces, as well as their compliance with building regulations and guidelines.

## Work Experience & Projects

- 2001 2005: Lead Designer of Design Studio "Khatynka", company Alex-RLH, Ltd.
- 2005 February 2022: Co-owner & Lead Designer at Design Studio "Khatynka". During this time, the following projects have been created:

2018 – 2022: Working on the "Casa De Coccinelle" project: luxury bungalows with a golf course. The full scope of work: landscape design, architectural design of the buildings, the interior design of the spaces, and advanced development of the project concept — from the logo to the menu.

2017: Summer House "Sokoli", creation of the architectural and landscape projects, development of the planning solution.

2016: Interior design of the attic room of a countryside mansion.

2015 – 2018: Reconstruction of 2-storey house "Sovki" in the centre of Kyiv, redevelopment of the planning solution, creation of additional spaces, new colour and interior solution.

2013 – 2014: Design of interior solution for office and warehouse of an American company, creation, and elaboration of functional connections of premises for successful functioning and creation of effective communication between office and warehouse.

2012: Reconstruction of luxury apartments in the historical centre of Kyiv, development of re-planning and layout solutions considering the preservation of the historical image of the interior, necessary to preserve the authenticity of the interior.

2011: Design of automobile service station "Auto-doctor", development of design concept taking into account the technical processes required for the successful functioning of the business.

2008: Design of residential house building "Victoria" with simultaneous placement of residential and commercial premises for business.

2007: Design of Drive-in Cinema "Saloon": creating a concept with elements of the Wild West style, taking into account the wishes of the customer, the development of traffic schemes and parking spaces, safe traffic of pedestrians and staff, the creation of technical rooms for maintenance of the cinema.

2006: Design of children's theatre with 300 seats, planning solution, the interior solution with consideration of all technical processes and functional connections of the premises necessary for safe and comfortable accommodation of the audience.

2004: Magazine office of the "Atelier" publishing house, for 27 employees, separation of the rooms into different departments, fully taking into account all professional needs of the publishing house, from magazine layout to delivery of the finished print product to the publishers.

2004: Design of the "Praonuka" summer house's interior and its complete realization, with the goal of selling by the client.

2003 – 2017: Project for the renovation and restoration of the brewery building "Kanskiy Brewery" dated 1879. Work on the restoration of the building's façades, restoration of the roof, and creation of interior solutions, taking into account the technological processes and features required for the production of malt and beer.

2003 – 2007: Interior projects for the mobile phone shop chain "Mobile-service".

2003 – 2004: Designs of interiors for five retail shops for subsequent rental.

2003 – 2004: Project of a house "Sovki" for a family of three persons, architectural solution, planning solution, interior solution, full-cycle landscaping with the creation of 2 artificial ponds, waterfall, and a stream, combined into one circulating system, arrangement of footpaths, lawn creation, planting.

2003 – 2004: Developer of interior projects for 9 apartments/flats (2, 3 and 4 room-flats), redevelopment, interior solutions and furniture schemes creation, followed by supervision for the client until the project is completed.

2002: Office of a mobile phone company "Mobile-service".

2001: Project of the office premises of the "Khatynka" design studio with a sales room.

1995: Restaurant Complex "Pomaranch" with 5 halls (general, banquet, billiard room, for confidential meetings). Redevelopment, and creation of the concept, style, and furniture.

1995: Hairdresser's shop planning, furniture design, style development.

1994: Shop "Pleasant goods" — planning, conception, style, and furnishing development.

1993: Coffee Shop "RLH", redevelopment of the existing building to meet the needs and requirements of the coffee shop.

#### Education

- May 1992: Courses of management and marketing with the speciality of Manager-Organizer for commercial activities.
- 1999 2005: Kyiv, Ukraine: Graduated from the College of Art Modelling and Design in 2005, specialising in Design, and qualified as an Interior Designer.
- 2005 2006: Kyiv, Ukraine: Graduated from the College of Art Modelling and Design in 2006, with a basic degree in Art and qualified as a Bachelor of Design, Interior Designer.
- 2006 2007: Kyiv, Ukraine: Graduated from the Private Higher Education Institution "Artistic Modelling and Design Institute" in 2007 and received a full higher education in Design and qualified as an Environment Designer.